Revenge is back in fashion
The Dressmaker is a drama, comedy, western film directed by Jocelyn Moorhouse.
In 1950s Australia, beautiful, talented dressmaker Tilly returns to
her tiny hometown to right wrongs from her past.
As she tries to reconcile with her mother, she starts to fall in
love while transforming the fashion of the town.
Myrtle "Tilly" Dunnage, played by Kate Winslet.
Teddy McSwiney, played by Liam Hemsworth.
Elsbeth Beaumont, played by Caroline Goodall.
Molly Dunnage, played by Judy Davis.
Prudence, played by Hayley Magnus.
Sergeant Farrat, played by Hugo Weaving.
The Dressmaker is a 2015 comedy drama film co-written and directed by Jocelyn
Moorhouse, based on the 2000 novel of the same title by Rosalie Ham.
It stars Kate Winslet as femme fatale dressmaker, Myrtle "Tilly" Dunnage, who returns to a
small Australian town to take care of her ailing, mentally unstable mother.
The film explores the themes of revenge and creativity and was described by
Moorhouse as "Clint Eastwood's Unforgiven with a sewing machine".
The film was internationally co-financed between
Australia and the United States.
The project was first conceived in 2000, and Ham wrote a
treatment herself which was not developed.
Sue Maslin bought the rights to the novel and hired
Moorhouse to direct and write the screenplay.
Production took place in Melbourne and across Victoria, Australia in late 2014.
The film had its world premiere at 2015 Toronto International Film Festival on 14 September 2015
and had a theatrical release on 29 October 2015 in Australia and New Zealand.
It opened at the number 1 spot at the Australian and New Zealand box offices and became the second highest-grossing
Australian film of 2015 and sixteenth highest-grossing film of all time at Australian box office.
Despite receiving mixed critical reviews, with praise going towards Winslet's performance and criticism
focusing on its uneven tone, The Dressmaker led the 5th AACTA Awards with thirteen nominations.
These included Best Film, Best Direction, Best Production Design, Best Original Music Score, Best Sound, Best Editing, Best Cinematography and won Best
Lead Actress, Best Supporting Actress, Best Supporting Actor, Best Costume Design and People's Choice Award for Favourite Australian Film.
The film explores themes of australia, small town, based on
novel or book, suppressed past, dark comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.